# WENDY HUANG

I want to build tools for humans

M melonh0327@gmail.com

https://melonhuang.github.io

**(86)18588640327** 

## SUMMARY

I'm a Senior Front-End Engineer with 4 years working experience. Crafting interesting and useful tools is my jam. In the recent past, I have given talks at development conferences, started several open source projects, and actively participated in the translation of technical books.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Qihoo 360 Technology Co. Lt

2013 - 2017

Senior Front-End Developer - Annual Excellent Employee of department

#### An online presentation editor - Shengxiang

2016 - 2017

- Led a team of four Front-End developers, enforced coding standards, kept the group engaged and passionate.
- Designed predictable, scalable architecture with Vue&Vuex (React&Redux alike Javascript libraries).
- Automated workflow for development, testing, and production environment with Gulp, Webpack, PostCSS, etc.
- Designed database tables and implemented Back-End logics and APIs using ThinkJS (a Back-End MVC Framework).
- Designed innovative features and transformed them into coordinated ART and IT deliverables.

## An interactive mobile storytelling platform - Baomitu

2015 - 2016

Built componentized architecture by designing Nova.js (a web component framework like Polymer).

#### **Mobile Guard Department**

2014 - 2015

- Developed official websites, mobile-side pages for special events and cross-device webviews.
- Made quick response and decisions to several independent and concurrent requirements every day, while making effective plans and guaranteeing high quality deliverables.
- Delivered high performance and compatible cross-device web pages.
- Designed NovaUI (an open source mobile-side component gallery) to share common mobile-side components with the other engineers.

2013 - 2014 **CRM System** 

- Wrote consistent, concise, and well documented codes to build pages full of form manipulations and charts.
- Abstracted and designed common plugins for reusability.

## OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

Nova.js 2015 - 2016

A production-ready Web Component Framework, only 12KB after gziped, providing an easy way to define custom element with data binding, CSS Scoping, etc.

2013 - 2016

A mobile side component gallery with high animation performance, flexible APIs and clear documents.

**AnimationGenerator** 2014 - 2014

A Chrome Devtools extension which can help generate animation codes for web pages quickly.



#### The 2nd CSSConf of China

High Performance Animation

## Other talks

How Browser Renders, Mobile-side Development, Web Component, etc



## **PLUBLICATIONS**

### Large Scale Javascript

Translated Chapters 8 - 19 from English to Madarine

#### The Mobile Handbook

Translated Chapters 3 - 4 from English to Mandarine

# EDUCATION

## Sun Yat-sen University

Software Engineering BSc 2009 - 2013



## **Modern Web Stack**

- HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, DOM scripting
- Mobile-Side development, responsive web design
- Node.js and MVC Back-End Framework
- Network knowleges including HTTP protol, TCP handshakes, etc
- Fullstack, able to design database tables, implement Back-End logics and design UI
- Good documenting habit

## Rich Experience in

- Performance Optimization
- Large-scale web applications, designing scalable architecture and workflow
- Javascript Application Framework Vue.js
- o Cross-browser and cross-device development, handling compatibility issues

#### Tools

- o npm, gulp, webpack, postCSS, babel, thinkjs, eslint, mocha.js, chai.js, etc
- vim, git/svn, chrome devtools, photoshop, zsh, etc
- Vue.js, Polymer, jQuery, Zepto, etc